Let's talk about three traversal traversing a tree means visiting every note in the tree.
You might, for instance, want to add all the values in that tree or find the largest one for all these
operations you fight, you need to visit each node of the tree.
Linear data structures like arrays, stack you and link list have only one way to read that data, but
a hierarchical data structure like a tree can be traversed in different ways.
So consider this tree.
You can read this tree by many ways.
So let's think about how we can read the elements of the tree in the image shown below.
You can read like this from top to the roots and then nine.
So from the top one, 12, five, six and nine.
If we start from the bottom so we can read.
It was five, six, 12, nine and one.
We are moving from each level under each level.
We start from the left to the right and then we go up to the second level.
We will see does it traverse through A. of the of the three that we have route, the note of the the
structure of the note contains the data and struck note left the pointer to the left and struck note
to the right pointer to the right.
So the struck note point that the two by the left and right might have other left and right shoulder,
so we should think of them as secretary instead of sub notes.
OK, according to this structure, every tree is a combination of a note carrying data and that dos
threes.
Let's say the order of traversal.
In order traversal, post order traversal and pre order traversal.
I have noted that left L R the R, what does this means left root and dry.
I memorized them by this in order so the road would be in the middle, depending on.
Depending on the order on which we do this, there are there can be three types of traversal.
But first of all, we will start by making inorder travels, OK?
So.
Start by visiting this order in order traversal.
Start by visiting all the nodes in the left tree, then the root node, then visit all the nodes to
the right sub three.
OK.
And this is their algorithm of in order travails left the road and dry.
Let's look an example.
This is that route.
So as I told you, we start in this in order traversal by substituting and subtracting like segmenting
that three into three parts, the route that left part and the right part and the from the left part,
we see that there is a sub tree.
So I need to also sub it like segment it into a route into left and right parts.
Till now, every note in this tree is segmented.
Know that in order traversal, start with the left part, so we go to the root and left.
We start by display the root data and then in order the route to the right.
So output, what is the output or how we read this tree in order traversal?
We start from the top, though, is the route, so we didn't start from the route, we need to start
from the left side.
We go down to 12 12 is a route, so we we don't read it.
We continue to turn left by going to five five.
Have children?
No.
And it is on the left side.
Yes, it is on the left side.
So we start by printing the five again again.
Five.
There is no route or sorry if there is no children's children.
So five is being great or that correct?
We go up.
What is the root of five?
It is 12.
Okay, so left route right.
Left is five.
Route 12 and right is six.
You see, guys, this is the algorithm.
This is that in order traversal, we start from the most.
And that note to the left going to row route and then we go to the right.
Then we have finished it from five 12 and say, this is the left part of the route.
The route one, which is one.
So this the left, this is the left part.
We have finished the left part of the main three.
We go from the left.
We go to the root, what is the root of this three?
It is one, so we print one.
And what is the right segment of the of this?
Three.
It is nine.
So this is that in order to reverse.
Let's see.
The other pre-order traversal.
OK, let's see the other two at traversing orders.
It is called a pre-order traversal.
We start from the route, we go to the left and we go then to the right.
OK, we start from displaying the data of the route.
We you go to the pre-order going to the left, left, left and right.
Right, right.
OK, we start output.
What is the output of this three?
We start.
What is the root of this three?
It is one.
So we print one.
What is the left of this three?
It is a sub three that contains 12 as a root left to the left.
Note five and right Note six.
So this is the this is that three, 12, five and six, but since we are using a pre ordered reversal.
So we start with Ruth.
So there's 12.
Then we go to the left of this tree, which is five, so we print five and then we go to the right of
this sub tree, which is six.
And since we have finished the left part of the main tree, so we have finished the route, which is
one we have finished the left, which is 12, five and six.
We go to the right, which is nine.
And this is the pre-order reversal route left and right.
Please write these down on your copy.
Book on your notebook because they are very important and they are asked in many university exams and
many interview questions.
Okay.
Let's see the last order traversal, which has left a root and right.
So we start by visiting all nodes in the left up tree XEM.
Visit all the nodes in the rights of tree.
And last we visit that route.
Note.
What is the last part?
It is.
Twelve.
Five and six.
OK, this is the sub three of the four, the main man, three.
But what is the left part of this sub?
Three?
It is five.
We start by five.
What is the right of the sub three?
It is six.
What is the root of this sub tree?
There's 12.
And this is the left part of the main artery we go through nine, because this is their algorithm,
this is the post order traversal.
And when we finish all the nodes, we specify the main error, which is what OK, I need from you to
do to memorize these post order traversal in order traversal and pre or traversal ways because they
are very important and all of our work will be concentrated on these.